Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records
Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records
1905-1993
Albert Schweitzer Fellowship.
34 linear ft.
Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records includes Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records (office files, board of directors records, financial records, programs and projects, and publications); Albert Schweitzer Hospital records (communications, medical reports, publications, hospital construction including photographs, blueprints, and financial records, U.S. A.I.D. grant, subject files); Association internationale de l'Hôpital Albert Schweitzer (communications, subject files, publications); Albert Schweitzer Center records (communications and publications); Schweitzer Memorabilia (Albert Schweitzer documents, Helene Schweitzer documents, Schweitzer-related materials, material by and about Schweitzer in various languages). Correspondents include Erica Anderson, Theodor Binder, Jorge Bird, Julius Seelye Bixler, E. Gaine Cannon, Frank Catchpool, Norman Cousins, A.R.T. Denues, Lee and Dottie Ellerbrock, Ford Foundation, Maurice Frey, Lawrence Gussman, Hermann Hagedore, Jerome Hill, Homer A. Jack, Charles Joy, George T. Keating, Reinhard N. Lahde, Leif Erikson Foundation, Charles Lowe, Hans Margolius, Emmy Martin, Louis Mayer, William Maul Measey, William Larimer Mellon, Joseph F. Montague, Edouard Nies-Berger, Simon Obame-Bikoro, Leslie Paffrath, Laura Person, R.P. Dominique Pire, Fergus Pope, Thomas D. Rees, Myrta Ross, Ali Silver, Ruth Sloan, Keith Smith, Isaac N.P. Stokes, Margaret S. Tenbrinck, Paul Dudley White, Andre Wick, V. McKinley Wiles, and Elizabeth L. Young.
149501
Biographical History
The Albert Schweitzer Fellowship (ASF) was founded by American friends of Albert Schweitzer in 1939 to support his hospital and medical work at Lambarene in Gabon (then French Equatorial West Africa), and to disseminate his philosophical and ethical principles, characterized by the phrase "reverence for life."
The ASF was involved in direct support of the hospital through fund-raising and material gifts until operation of the hospital was assumed by the Gabonese government, two years after Schweitzer's death in 1965. Presently, the ASF continues to support the work of the hospital through lobbying for U.S. government aid and raising funds for capital improvements. In 1979, it instituted an internship program at the hospital for visiting Harvard Medical School students.
ASF leaders helped to organize Albert Schweitzer's only visit to the U.S., in 1949, to deliver a lecture on Goethe. The ASF has been active in publishing and disseminating writings, recordings, and films by and about Schweitzer. ASF records include a great volume of both published and unpublished materials. A major project was the compilation of a Schweitzer Bibliography, published in 1981.
The ASF organized two American conferences on Schweitzer, in 1966 and 1977, as well as celebrations of his centenary in 1975. In pursuit of Schweitzer's ethics, it remains active in numerous humanitarian and peace projects, particularly nuclear disarmament.
The ASF has been in constant communication with other Schweitzer-related organizations: (1) the Albert Schweitzer Hospital in Lambarene, (2) the numerous European organizations also dedicated to Schweitzer's work and ethics, under the umbrella of the Association internationale de l'Hopital Albert Schweitzer a Lambarenê et de son Oeuvre (A.I.S.L.) in which ASF itself is active, and (3) the Albert Schweitzer Center in Great Barrington, Massachusetts, founded in 1966 by Schweitzer's friend and filmmaker, Erica Anderson. The ASF records include a great deal of correspondence, reports, and publications from these organizations.
Due to its dedication to Schweitzer, to the personal friendship of early leaders with him, and to ongoing participation in the ASF by Schweitzer's daughter, Rhena Schweitzer Miller, the records include a substantial amount of memorabilia from Schweitzer, his wife Helene Schweitzer, and extensive publications and clippings files.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records have been divided into several series which reflect its filing practices. Inclusive dates for the collection are 1905-1992, the bulk of which is 1950-1987. A minor correspondence file dated 1990-1992 and some publications dating through 1993 are presently included in this collection; all other records are 1987 or earlier.
The Albert Schweitzer Fellowship series is the largest, comprising over half of the records. It is also the most complex, with four subseries as follows.
ASF Office Files: General records of the ASF were filed annually in folders marked "ASF". This series is an encompassing collection of general correspondence, and other material regarding the ASF, Albert Schweitzer, and related topics. Prior to 1972, it includes agendas, minutes, and handouts from Fellowship meetings. From 1945 to 63, while Albert Schweitzer himself was an active correspondent, several folders include lists and annotations for his letters. Only copies of letters from Schweitzer are now included here: all existing originals are filed under Schweitzer Memorabilia.
The organization of the Office Files is not consistent. Before about 1970, much general correspondence was filed separately, in alphabetical order and with several named files. These have been arranged as a subseries of the ASF Office Files. It should be noted that not all correspondence from particular individuals is contained in these files, even within the inclusive dates of a given file. This is especially true for active fellowship members. The volume and complexity of the records precluded a more systematic reorganization of this material.
Among the Office Files were scattered files on particular subjects. In other cases, the Office Files contained an extensive amount of material on a topic of distinct significance. These have been arranged in a subseries of subject files, which include numerous published and unpublished writings and a wide range of other material.
Board of Directors: This subseries overlaps with the Office Files, but focusses upon the official business of the ASF, including agendas, minutes, financial reports, other handouts from meetings, and rosters of the board of directors. From 1975 through 1983, it includes correspondence between the ASF office in New York and members of the board of directors; after 1983 Board of Directors correspondence is filed as a distinct subseries.
Financial Records: This subseries is self-explanatory. The records include numerous correspondence files kept for donors, who often enclosed personal notes, requests, and clippings, and ASF responses to donors.
ASF Programs and Projects and ASF Publications: These two subseries reflect various activities of the ASF in fulfilling its goals regarding Schweitzer's medical and ethical legacy through program sponsorship, U.N. and U.S. government policy initiatives, educational and public relations work, and fund-raising.
The next three series, Albert Schweitzer Hospital, A.I.S.L., and Albert Schweitzer Center, are similar in structure: all include a Communications subseries which, like the ASF Office Files, includes correspondence, agendas and minutes of meetings, other reports, and some conference papers. Much original material in the first two series is written in French (primarily) or German, although translations are generally also included.
Each series also includes a collection of the publications of the respective organizations, that of the A.I.S.L. and its constituent members being the most extensive. A number of subject files are attached to the Hospital and A.I.S.L. series. The Hospital series also includes a subseries of medical reports and statistics.
The final series, Schweitzer memorabilia, includes (1) correspondence (originals, copies and translations) and other writings by Albert Schweitzer, (2) letters, clippings, and an article by Helene Schweitzer, and (3) numerous Schweitzer-related publications, as well as a great volume of clippings, from both American and international sources. A substantial collection (three boxes) of Printed Matter, mostly popular and scholarly periodicals with articles about Schweitzer, is filed by decade of publication. The final box of the records contains a number of books, periodicals, and pamphlets collected by the ASF, in numerous languages; a list of authors, titles, and dates is provided in the finding aid.
Arrangement of the Collection
The ASF stored files in reverse chronological order, and this arrangement has been maintained. Individual records within folders were generally filed in no obvious order, and where possible or practical these have been rearranged into reverse chronological order as well.
Related Material
See also the
Albert Schweitzer Papers
.
Separated Material
Thirty-one reels of audio recordings have been removed to permanent storage in the Belfer Sound Archives of Syracuse University. A memorandum regarding these is attached to the finding aid.
Subject and Genre Headings
Activism and social reform; Religion and philosophy; Science and medicine; Anderson, Erica.; Bixler, Julius Seelye, 1894-1985.; Cousins, Norman.; Denues, A. R. T. (Arthur Russell Taylor), 1914-; Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964.; Hill, Jerome, 1905-1972.; Jack, Homer A. (Homer Alexander), 1916-1993.; Joy, Charles R. (Charles Rhind), 1885-1978.; Keating, George T., 1892-; Margolius, Hans, 1902-; Measey, William Maul, 1875-1967.; Mellon, William Larimer, 1910-; Nies-Berger, Edouard.; Paffrath, Leslie.; Person, Laura.; Stokes, Isaac N. P. (Isaac Newton Phelps), 1906-; Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965.; Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965 -- Societies, etc.; White, Paul Dudley, 1886-1973.; Binder, Theodor.; Bird, Jorge.; Cannon, E. Gaine.; Catchpool, Frank.; Ellerbrock, Dottie.; Ellerbrock, Lee.; Frey, Maurice.; Gussman, Lawrence.; Lahde, Reinhard N.; Lowe, Charles.; Martin, Emmy.; Mayer, Louis.; Montague, Joseph F.; Obame-Bikoro, Simon.; Pire, R. P. Dominique.; Pope, Fergus.; Rees, Thomas D.; Ross, Myrta.; Silver, Ali.; Sloan, Ruth.; Smith, Keith.; Schweitzer, Helene.; Tenbrinck, Margaret S.; Wick, Andre.; Wiles, V. McKinley; Young, Elizabeth L.; Albert Schweitzer Fellowship -- History.; Albert Schweitzer Fellowship -- Political activity.; Ford Foundation.; Leif Erikson Foundation.; Charities, Medical.; Endowments -- United States.; Voluntary hospitals -- Gabon.; Humanitarianism.; Missionaries, Medical.; Missions, Medical -- Gabon.; Peace -- Societies, etc.; Agendas (administrative records); Articles.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Financial records.; Manuscripts (document genre); Manuscripts for publication.; Medical records.; Minutes (administrative records); Photographs.; Professional papers.; Project files.; Publications.; Speeches (documents)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Albert Schweitzer Fellowship, 1993.
Inventory
- Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records
  - ASF office files
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1975-1987 (Box 1)
      - 1968-1974 (Box 2)
      - 1941-1967 (Box 3)
      - Membership communications, 1984 (Box 3)
      - Clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
      - Material gifts for hospital, 1955-1972; correspondence (Box 3)
      - Charles Lowe, 1968-1970; correspondence (Box 3)
      - Rhena Schweitzer [Miller], 1962-1969; correspondence and trips (Box 3)
      - Harold Williams, 1967; correspondence and reports (Box 3)
      - Visitors to Lambarene, 1955-1962; correspondence (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1954-1966 (Box 4)
      - Anderson, Erica, 1951-1968 (Box 4)
        For her two films and two books, see ASF Office Files: Subject Files (Boxes 7-8); see also Albert Schweitzer Center (Box 28).
      - B, 1953-1967 (Box 4)
      - Binder, Dr. Theodor (Peru Hospital), 1956-1965 (Box 4)
      - Bird, Jorge, 1968 (Box 4)
      - Bixler, Julius Seelye, 1944-1965 (Box 4)
      - C, 1952-1968 (Box 4)
      - Cannon, E. Gaine, 1957-1971 (Box 4)
      - Catchpool, Frank, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
      - Cousins, Norman, 1952-1969 (Box 4)
      - D, 1956-1965 (Box 4)
      - Denues, A. R. T. (CANCIRCO), 1962-1968 (Box 4)
      - DuBois, W.E.B., See Subject files: Guide to Albert Schweitzer Collections (Box 6)
      - E, 1954-1970 (Box 4)
      - Ellerbrock, Lee and Dottie, 1955-1970 (Box 4)
      - F, 1956-1966 (Box 4)
      - Ford Foundation, 1952-1954 (Box 4)
      - Frey, Maurice, 1962-1964 (Box 4)
      - G, 1960-1966 (Box 4)
      - Gussman, Lawrence, 1957-1966 (Box 4)
      - H, 1956-1966 (Box 4)
      - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1954-1961 (Box 4)
        Additional material may be found in the
        Hermann Hagedorn Papers
        .
      - Hill, Jerome, 1952-1967 (Box 4)
      - J, 1955-1969 (Box 4)
      - Jack, Homer A., 1955-1962 (Box 4)
      - Joy, Charles, 1950-1966 (Box 4)
        See also Smith, Keith. See Schweitzer Memorabilia: Photographs (Box 29) for photos by Joy. Additional material may be found in the
        Charles Joy papers.
      - K, 1953-1962 (Box 4)
      - L, 1927-1971 (Box 4)
      - Leif Erikson Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
      - M, 1954-1971 (Box 4)
      - Margolius, Hans, 1950-1968; includes various writings (Box 4)
      - Martin, Emmy, 1948-1963 (Box 4)
      - Mayer, Louis, 1953-1968 (Box 4)
      - Mellon, William Larimer, 1962-1970 (Box 4)
      - Montague, Joseph F., 1964 (Box 4)
      - N, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
      - Nies-Berger, Edouard, 1961-1966 (Box 4)
      - O, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
      - Obame-Bikoro, Simon, 1963-1970 (Box 5)
      - P, 1953-1964 (Box 5)
      - Paffrath, Leslie, 1954-1970 (Box 5)
      - Pire, R. P. Dominique, 1960-1964 (Box 5)
      - Pope, Fergus, 1964-1966 (Box 5)
      - R, 1953-1966 (Box 5)
      - Rees, Thomas D., 1962-1967 (Box 5)
      - Ross, Myrta, 1957; 1971-1972 (Box 5)
      - S, 1957-1971 (Box 5)
      - Silver, Ali, 1954-1970 (Box 5)
      - Sloan, Ruth, 1962-1967 (Box 5)
      - Smith, Keith, 1960-1967; includes anthology of Schweitzer quotations compiled by Charles Joy (Box 5)
      - Stokes, Isaac N. P., 1956-1969 (Box 5)
      - T, 1954-1968 (Box 5)
      - Tenbrinck, Margaret S., 1962-1964; includes three published articles (Box 5)
      - U, 1957-1967 (Box 5)
      - W, 1955-1967 (Box 5)
      - White, Paul Dudley, 1959-1971 (Box 5)
      - Wick, Andre, 1954-1970 (Box 5)
      - Wiles, V. McKinley, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
      - XYZ, 1955-1964 (Box 5)
      - Requests for information
        - Correspondence A-M, 1950-1972 (Box 5)
        - Correspondence N-Z, 1950-1972 (Box 6)
    - Subject files
      - Schweitzer-related Associations (list), 1984 (Box 6)
      - New York State Schweitzer and Einstein Chairs, 1984 (Box 6)
      - Schweitzer-related writings, 1971-1982; includes items by Hans Margolius, Ernest Mayer, Mickey Goddard, Douglas Steere, Erich Fromm, Manuel M. Davenport (Box 6)
      - Guide to Albert Schweitzer Collections, 1979-1982; includes correspondence, clippings, exchange of letters between Albert Schweitzer and W.E.B. DuBois (photocopied), published guide (1981) (Box 6)
      - Schweitzer bibliography, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
      - Schweitzer Nobel Prize Address, 1978; reprint for U.N. session, includes correspondence, address by Lawrence Gussman, paste-up, ASF Courier issue (Box 6)
        See also Schweitzer Memorabilia: Albert Schweitzer Documents: Nobel Prize Address for the original in French (Box 28) and Schweitzer-related materials: Clippings: Nobel Prize (Box 30)
      - Wingspread Symposium
        - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6)
        - Writings, 1977 (Box 6)
          Includes program; papers by Michael A. Diana, David Laird Dungan, Lawrence Gussman, Richard H. Hiers, Jackson Lee Ice, Homer A. Jack, Ruth Harriet Jacobs, Michael F. Kipp, Leonard T. Kurland, Antje Bultmann Lemke, George N. Marshall, David C. Miller, Lorus J. and Margery Milne, Caroline L. Moseley, Robert Muller, Christine Stevens, Richard Torrence, Ronald Emerson Wolfe
        - Session transcripts, 1977 (Box 6)
        - Financial, 1977 (Box 6)
      - Audio recordings of Wingspread discussion sessions (1977), luncheon (1/14/65), and unknown, 1965; includes program from Rotary Club luncheon and memo on transfer of tape reels to Belfer Sound Archives for permanent storage (Box 6)
    - Schweitzer bibliography project (Laura Person)
      - Laura Person
        - Records, 1958-1960; includes photograph of Laura Person, some correspondence with bibliographic entries, report and expense accounts for ASF (Box 6)
        - Correspondence, 1954-1974 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence with international libraries, 1955-1961; includes bibliographic lists from several countries in Europe, and Japan (Box 7)
      - Princeton University Library, 1956-1986; includes publications and correspondence, chiefly between Laura Person and Howard C. Rice (Box 7)
      - Book lists, 1949-1969 (Box 7)
      - Articles and exhibits, 1954-1964; includes lists of newspaper and magazine articles on Schweitzer in America and Europe (Box 7)
      - Microfilms from European publications, 1917-1944 (Box 7)
        Includes series of articles in Spanish by Luise Bresslan Hoff (Poligrafia, 1944); cover pages from Lettres de l'Hopital du Dr. Albert Schweitzer a Lambarene (1930-39), Schweitzer's article, "A New Bow for Unaccompanied Violin Music" ( Musical Times, 1933), two articles by Schweitzer and an obituary for Louis Schweitzer in the periodical ElsassLothringischer Familien-Kalender (1926, 29); a series of Swiss articles in German (about Bach's St. Matthew Passion?)
    - Agency for International Development, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
    - Surrey, Karasik and Morse, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Biafra Project, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
    - Film, Living Work of Albert Schweitzer / Erica Anderson, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
    - Lions International (Biafra), 1967-1969 (Box 7)
    - Walter Munz' visit, 1967-1969; correspondence and clippings (Box 7)
    - Miriam Rogers; Boston Friends of Albert Schweitzer
      - 1950-1968 (Box 7)
      - Financial records, 1951-1964 (Box 7)
    - Albert Schweitzer Amazon Hospital
      - Theodor Binder, 1956-1968 (Box 8)
      - Records, 1959-1965 (Box 8)
    - Book, Schweitzer Album / Erica Anderson, 1965-1967; clippings (Box 8)
    - Seven Arts Television (film, Schweitzer's Africa), 1966-1967 (Box 8)
    - Aspen Convocation on Albert Schweitzer
      - Program and writings, 1966 (Box 8)
        Includes writings by Rhena Schweitzer Eckert, Norman Cousins, Antonia Brico, David Miller, D. A. Werner, Frederick Diekert, Frank Catchpool, Henry Clark, James Pike, John Everett, Waldemar Nielson; two additional writings of Rhena Schweitzer, in French, are included, about her father and reports about the Lambarene hospital
      - Correspondence and clippings, 1966 (Box 8)
      - Clippings, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Reviews of Schweitzer biographies, 1947-1965 (Box 8)
    - Animal Welfare Institute, Schweitzer, 1951-1965 (Box 8)
    - David Blum, Esterhazy Orchestra, 1958-1965 (Box 8)
    - Book, Albert Schweitzer's Gift of Friendship / Erica Anderson, 1964-1965; clippings (Box 8)
    - Unitarian Program on Albert Schweitzer, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Hanna Oberman, 1952-1963; correspondence and visit (Box 8)
    - Columbia Records, 1952-1963; correspondence and clippings (Box 8)
    - Proposed Legal Agreement between Albert Schweitzer and ASF, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Film, Albert Schweitzer / Erica Anderson, 1955-1961; includes correspondence, legal and financial papers, invitations, advertisements (Box 8)
    - Herbert Phillips, Albert Schweitzer Education Foundation, 1955-1961 (Box 8)
    - Frederick S. Franck, 1958-1961 (Box 8)
    - Cathedral Films, 1961; correspondence (Box 8)
    - Typescript, At Home with Albert Schweitzer / Borge Friis, 1961(?) (Box 8)
    - Albert Schweitzer Elementary School (Pennsylvania), 1960 (Box 8)
    - Radio and television broadcasts, 1949-1957 (Box 8)
    - Schweitzer Hospital Fund, Marion Mill Preminger, 1954-1957; includes formal papers, correspondence with Mrs. Marion Preminger (Box 8)
    - Emma Haussknecht visit (1953-1954), 1953-1956 (Box 9)
    - Marionette Play, Oganga (Elisabeth L. Young), 1954; includes script with dedication (in French) to Schweitzer, program, photographs, clippings (Box 9)
      See also Financial records: Receipts: Contribution correspondence: Young, Elisabeth L. (Mrs. James) (Box 14)
    - Schweitzer-related writings, 1946-1950; includes items by Emory Ross (3), Everett Skillings (Box 9)
    - Schweitzer visit to U.S., 1949 (Box 9)
    - Aspen Lecture on Goethe (English), 1949 (Box 9)
  - Board of directors
    - 1979-1987 (Box 9)
    - 1975-1978 (Box 10)
    - 1972 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee, 1964-1968 (Box 10)
  - Financial records
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1987; includes bank statements, annual financial reports, correspondence regarding finances, nonprofit forms (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967-1975 (Box 12)
    - Cash disbursement Ledger, 1962-1979 (Oversize 1)
    - Expenditures, 1985-1987 (Box 12)
    - Expenditures, 1984 (Box 13)
    - Expenditures, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Receipts
      - 1982-1987, includes bequest documentation (Box 13)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 13)
      - 1972 (Box 13)
      - Contributions, correspondence
        - Miscellaneous, 1990-1992 (Box 13)
        - A-C, 1953-1971 (Box 13)
        - D-G, 1953-1971 (Box 13)
        - H-K, 1953-1970 (Box 14)
        - Keating, George T., 1949-1971 (Box 14)
        - L-M, 1953-1970 (Box 14)
        - Lande, Reinhard N., 1960-1971 (Box 14)
        - Measey, William Maul, 1956-1964 (Box 14)
        - N-R, 1953-1970 (Box 14)
        - S, 1953-1970 (Box 14)
        - T-Z, 1953-1970 (Box 14)
        - Young, Elisabeth L. (Mrs. James), 1957-1969 (Box 14)
          See also Subject files: Marionette Play, Oganga (Elisabeth L. Young) (Box 9)
        - Contributor lists, 1946-1964 (Box 14)
        - Contribution logs, 1947-1959 (Box 14)
        - Receipt forms, 1985-1987 (Box 14)
        - Receipt forms, 1977-1984 (Box 15)
        - Receipt forms, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
      - Gifts of securities, 1953-1970 (Box 16)
      - Bequests, 1949-1972 (Box 16)
    - Auditor's statements, 1956-1986 (Box 16)
    - Brown Brothers Harriman & Co., 1956-1971 (Box 17)
    - Chemical Bank New York Trust, 1956-1966 (Box 17)
    - Insurance, 1966 (Box 17)
    - Tax reports, 1947-1965 (Box 17)
    - Bonds for hospital pensions, 1948-1956; 1965 (Box 17)
    - Financial statements, 1946-1958 (Box 17)
    - Investment funds, 1948-1956 (Box 17)
    - Account books, 1939-1945 (Box 17)
  - ASF programs and projects
    - Medical Student Program
      - 1979-1987, includes application materials, correspondence, student reports (Box 18)
      - Subject files
        - Companion to Medical French, 1985 (Box 18)
        - Foundation Prospect List, 1982 (Box 18)
        - Manual for Interns, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Catholic University Program, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
    - 20th Anniversary Commemoration, 1985; includes typescript of article by Jack Impey, "Albert Schweitzer: Prophet of Life" (Box 18)
    - Dr. Stanley G. Browne
      - 1979-1983, includes materials relative to ASF's nomination of Browne for the Templeton Prize for Progress in Religion (Box 18)
      - Publications, 1959-1980 (Box 18)
    - Nobel Laureate Project
      - 1981-1982, includes letters signed by Menachem Begin, Norman Borlaug, Linus Pauling, Andrei Sakharov, and Mother Teresa (Box 18)
      - Lord Philip Noel-Baker, 1982; includes correspondence, speech, clippings, obituaries (Box 18)